Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to design our very first level.
To get started.
Select this task image and right click and go Sprite actions and create task that.
Open this up.
And if you slept anywhere on the tile set, you'll see the square.
Using the square, we can add collision to certain tiles on our Tulsa.
This square is quite big, so we can adjust the size of it by going through tile size.
And if I make this 16 by 16, this will adjust my square.
And if I select this block of my square and go add box, this is going to add some collision to this
tile map.
And later, when we design a level with the tar map, if asked to select the square, it's going to
have collision on it.
When I place it in my tile map, if we go over to colliding tiles and just click it, I'm going to add
some more collision to my tar map by selecting some squares and going add blocks and add blocks.
If you want to adjust the collision of a square, what you can do is select it, then go over to the
single editor and select this point on the square and move it down at this point and move it down.
This means that specific square is going to have this collision.
So you can do that if you want to get more precise collision.
But I'm just going to leave mine at the default.
Once you're happy with the colliding tiles that you've added, just go save and close this.
Then select the equals and just right click spread actions and make this a tile set.
We're not going to add any collision to this, but we're going to use this as background.
So maybe in our level we'll have some background trees, bushes and rocks.
We can close this and then we're going to create a new map.
So if we right click and go paper duty, set tile map and I'll call this level one, and if we double
click and open it up.
Let's select our asset.
And if I go to my map with let's make it something like 100 and let's make the map pie something like
15.
As the 15, maybe a bit high.
So I'll make it like ten.
So now I am going to set some tiles and place them around my map.
So if I select this whole square and then paste it here.
Oh, okay.
So it looks like there's a bit of a gap between each tile.
That is because under tile width and tile height, we need to change it.
So it is 16 by 16.
So it's the same as our tile set.
So if I go back to this and under tile width 16 and under tile height at 16 as well.
And we can see that makes it look a bit normal.
I'm just going to erase everything.
And now we're ready to design our level one.
So to start off with, I am going to have this edge.
And I'll just place it here.
And then we're going to have some cubes.
And then I'm going to block off this edge.
And quick tip.
If I just looked here and then go fill is now going to fill in all the area between here so you can
use the fill tool like that, then I'm going to have some steps.
So let me go back to my paint and I'll add some steps here.
Okay, I'm not going to do a quick timelapse of me designing this level.
Hello.
So I have finished designing my map so we can close this.
And then drag my title map.
It's kind of small, so let's make it 13 times bigger.
And make sure to position this in the same layer as our back actor.
So my player character is in layer 20 of the Y axis.
So I'm going to move my map to layer 20 off the y axis.
And just make sure your player character starts at the top of the map.
So I can go play and my map is looking pretty cool.
There's one more thing we can do for our map, and that is add some background effects for our map.
So if I close this and open up my level one.
Let's go add new layer.
And make sure that this layer is behind our layer one.
Then if we go and look for our deco style set and just select some trees.
Okay, so I can't select the whole tree.
So if we go to our deco tower set.
I make sure that our size is 16 by 16, because that's what we set it to in our time.
And if we go back, I can select some trees.
So I've already worked with this, but it's a good idea to place the trees one layer below the dirt
and make sure they are on the layer behind a layer one.
So if I position some trees like this and this and then go save.
And just to show you what I mean, if I could play.
We have some trees which are behind our level and it kind of looks cool when our player character walks
past these trees.
So I'm going to add some trees, bushes and rocks behind my level one.
So just do that now.
And if you want to have multiple layers, just add a new layer and we can have even more layers that
way.
Let's say I need my layer or behind my layer five.
I can have a tree behind a tree and it kind of looks quite cool.
So now position some trees, bushes and rocks in your level.
Okay, so I have finished doing that and now I go play.
We have designed our level one.
The Bushes look kind of a bit above the ground, so I may need to find a best model which kind of has
like it's a bit taller.
That way it look a bit better in my game.
But for now I think it's fine and I'm just going to delete this floor.
And that way it looks like my character, it's more in this level.
And then one more final touch.
I'm going to make my camera a bit more zoomed out.
So I go back to my player character.
Open them up.
Go to the viewport and slap my spring on.
That's increase its length to something like 2000.
You can play around with this, but I think the game will look a bit better if the camera is a bit further
away.
So something like this, I think that looks a bit better.
Maybe I need to make the map a bit smaller, but I can play around and adjust with that.
Okay.
So I reduce the size of my map to something like ten, and I think it looks a bit better.
And I'm also, if I go back to my level one map, I'm going to make the height something like 20.
And then I'm going to fill the bottom with.
This tile set that way.
It looks like mud underneath my player character because right now we just see the air and it looks
kind of weird.
So I'll go to layer one and I'm just going to fill this up with that.
So if I go play.
I think this looks a bit better.